亚马逊盆地的食人巨蟒
据说被土人供成神来祭拜
巨蟒长达四十尺
凶残至极
巨蟒不满于只是吞噬猎物
犹吐出未死的猎物 再杀一次
《狂蟒之灾》
求救! 救我
Please, help. Somebody, help.
紧急呼叫
This is an emergency Somebody, please.
(亚马逊丛林旅馆)
芙勒薇小姐
Miss Flores.
凯尔博士
Professor Cale.
请进 何时到的?
Come on in. When did you get in?
几天前 我问过向导
A couple days ago. I've been talking to some guides...
这部族的下落
hoping they might know the whereabouts of our tribe.
怎么样?
Any luck?
确实有这个部落存在
There's evidence to suspect that these people are out there...
能找到并研究
and can be found and studied.
我这么告诉赞助者
At least that's what I told the grant people.
向导说大概在这附近
My man thinks the tribe was here, between these two tributaries.
他曾见过标记
He found one of their markers.
很好
That's good.
也许真能找到
We may have a chance.
带我去 我拍下来
Get me there and I'll shoot it.
我相信 所以雇用你
I'm counting on that. That's why I hired you.
很好 非常感激
I'm glad you did. I appreciate it.
你是很好的导演
I wanted the best director I could get.
我们会是好伙伴
I think we'll make a good team.
你好狼狈 怎么了?
You're a mess. What happened to you?
被食人鱼攻击 差点没命
Just a small attack of piranha. Barely escaped with my life.
带另一桶油来
Bring the other fuel drums.
你起得真早啊!
Somebody's up awfully early.
今天是好日子
Well, today is a good day.
是吗?
Is that right?
对 我的老乡今天要当导演了
Not every day my homegirl from 'SC gets to direct her own documentary.
准备好了?
You ready?
我想是吧!
I think so.
很好
That's right.
- 恭喜 - 谢谢
- Congratulations. - Thanks.
何况还有他作伴
I see you made this a pleasure cruise.
你应该了解我
Come on. You know me.
工作时不谈感情
I don't mix business with pleasure.
若是经由这里呢?
What about if we go up through here?
往这里走
This way...
比较好
better.
否则后果自行负责
If not, I cannot be responsible.
好吧 只多走55公里
Well, it's only 55 kilometers out of the way.
没问题 安全第一
Shouldn't be a problem. Better safe than sorry.
- 早安 - 早安
- Morning. - Morning.
马泰 你懂我说的话
Mateo, you understand me?
我听得懂
Sure, I understand.
好 把船开过去 我要拍摄
Great. I need you to drift through that channel. I want some shots.
全听你的 大姐
As you say... cheffe.
- 请过目 - 谢了
- For your approval. - Thanks.
卫斯屈呢? 他应该到了
Where's Westridge? I know he checked in.
也许在睡美容觉
Probably catching up on his beauty sleep.
当心点!
Careful!
是葡萄酒!
Bordeaux!
易碎品!
Fragile!
很贵的酒!
Expensive wine!
真是的!
Christ!
早安
Morning.
早安 旅途如何?
Morning. How was your flight?
其实糟透了
A bloody nightmare.
还没结束
Ongoing, I think.
一个变焦镜
One zoom lens.
你! 拿到我房里去
You. Stow these in my room.
什么?
Excuse me?
我不是小妹 我是制片
I'm not the bellhop. I'm the production manager.
搬行李就更没问题
Then manage my things into my room.
自大的混球
One pompous ass.
有些文化 瞧得起你
In some cultures it's a sign of friendship and respect...
才叫你提
if someone asks you to carry their bags.
音效师 瞧这个吧!
Respect this, sound man.
卫斯屈 我是戴芮
Mr. Westridge... Terri Flores.
幸会
A pleasure.
凯尔给我看过你作品
Professor Cale lent me some of your short films.
我想它们...很不错
I thought they were... very promising.
这么热! 我们在赤道上?
God, it's hot. Are we exactly on the equator?
欢迎登船
Welcome aboard, I guess.
- 他喜欢你 - 你感觉到了?
- I think he likes you. - Oh, you felt that too?
噢 凯尔 你看起来就像法国制片家贾古斯
Damn, Cale, you look like a low budget-ass Jacques Cousteau.
谁知道你说什么
Whatever the hell that means.
很高兴见到你
Good to see you.
杰夫! 往内格罗河出发
Cheffe! Ready for Rio Negro.
大家再次检查装备
Everybody, double check your gear.
确定大家都在船上 别忘了带防虫液
Make sure it's on board. And pray you didn't forget your bug spray.
我们的探险由亚马逊河口出发
Our adventure begins 1,000 miles from the mouth of the mighty A mazon...
深入雨林区
deep in the heart of the rain forest.
从这里 我们将要进入未开发的蛮荒雨林
From here, we will travel up shallow tributaries and unexplored backwaters...
探索传说中的谜
in search of the elusive People of the Mist...
亚夏麻族
the Shirishama Tribe...
揭开雨林的神秘面纱
one of the last great mysteries of the rain forest.
是我还是丛林
Is it just me or does the jungle make you really...
令你如此性感?
really horny?
是丛林的气氛
No, I think it's the jungle.
真的 我只想做一件事
I'm serious. I've got one thing on my mind.
让我工作 行吗?
Can I work, please?
救命!
Help!
Help me!
我被困住了!
I'm stranded!
我的船搁浅了
My boat is stranded in the roots!
救我!
Help me!
救命!
Help!
那船上有个人!
There's a dude on the boat over there!
开向那艘船
Pull over to his boat!
我们接你过来
We'll bring you on board!
谢天谢地!
Thank the Lord for you!
感谢主!
Thank the Lord!
你受伤了?
You hurt?
你还好吗?
You okay?
船的推进器被撞坏了
My propeller tore off in the roots!
不能载你回去 我们往上游
We can't take you back to Manaus. We're headed upriver.
下个村落的人会帮我修船
At the next village, I know the people. They help me fix my boat.
抱歉给你们添麻烦
I sorry if I be trouble for you!
不用道歉
There's no need to apologize.
只是我们的船没坏
We're all at the mercy of our machines.
你的坏了
Yours broke.
原始捕鱼方式
Fish, river-style.
不错
Not bad.
下次要拍下来
We're going to have to get that on film next time.
会做生鱼片 你叫...
Ever work in a sushi bar, Mr?
萨朗 保罗萨朗
Sarone. Paul Sarone.
你从哪来的?
Where are you from?
巴拉圭
Paraguay.
是吗?
Really?
我本来想当祭司
I started out studying for the priesthood...
后来
but then...
想见识真实世界
I needed to see the real world.
就待在丛林里了
So I ended up in the jungle.
我适合这里
I seem to fit.
做不成祭司能做什么?
What does a failed priest do in the jungle?
做不成?
Fail?
谁说我做不成?
Who says I fail?
我不做而已
I didn't fail.
才怪
I'm sure you didn't.
现时靠何维生?
Well, what is your... calling now?
蛇
Snakes.
蛇?
Snakes?
我抓蛇
I catch them...
为动物园或收藏家
for zoos and collectors.
什么都抓
Anything.
盗猎?
Poaching?
盗猎是非法的 请问你们猎些什么?
Poaching is illegal. May I ask, what you are hunting?
我们什么都不捕猎
We're not hunting or trapping anything.
我们拍制纪录片
We're making a documentary on the...
关于西夏麻族
Shirishama Indians.
传说中的谜
The People of the Mist?
没错 你听过?
That's right. You've heard of them?
我看过
Seen them.
真的?
Really?
能告诉我们在哪里吗?
Could you show me where that was?
你们救了我的命
You people saved my life.
当然愿意
Least I can do.
我可以带你们去
I can show you exactly where I saw the Shirishama.
别听喝了五杯威士忌的醉鬼胡说
So slurs every other river rat after five whiskeys in any bar in Manaus.
拜托
Come on.
五杯威士忌?
Five whiskeys?
那只是早餐
That's breakfast on the river.
沙拉配着鱼吃对味吗?
Well, would a salad go well with "fish, river-style," Mr. Sarone?
沙拉很好
A salad would be perfect...
小丫头
little baby bird.
你看
Look at that.
那是荧火虫?
What are those? Fireflies?
很漂亮吧?
Pretty, huh?
鞘翅目类
Family Lampyridae.
聚集在一棵树上
On certain nights they all gather in the same tree and...
用亮光向异性示爱
use their white flashes to announce their readiness to mate.
公的还是母的发亮?
Who flashes? The males or the females?
都会发亮
Both, actually.
母的发光较短促
The females with a series of short, dainty...
每次持续约八秒
feminine little flashes, about eight per second.
公的以持续的发光热烈反应
The males respond with a series of long, drawn out, manly flashes.
我喜欢
I like that.
不用说废话 不会有误解
No pick up lines, no misunderstandings.
自然的本性
Just instinct and nature.
我想念你
I missed you.
妈的!
Shit!
吵死人了!
Bloody racket!
别碰我音响
Don't touch my radio!
当心我雇人宰了你
I could cheerfully hire someone to kill you.
找个土人 五十元就够了
A local tribesman, perhaps. Fifty dollars should cover it.
我能免费杀了你
Or I could kill you for free right now.
就凭你?
Oh, yeah.
你和谁呢?
You and whose army?
你妈啦!
Your mama's.
接近了吗?
Are we getting close?
就在这附近
Just around this bend.
太好了
Perfect.
蛇的图腾
A snake totem.
这图腾
This totem...
是西夏麻族的
is Shirishama.
他们祭拜巨蟒
Shirishama worship giant snakes...
视为守护神
anacondas, as gods and protectors.
据说有个神秘之湖
There's a legend they pass down of a journey to a sacred lake.
经过有巨蟒看守的瀑布
You pass a waterfall protected by warrior snakes.
一旦你通过那些守护神 就到达西夏麻族
Once you pass those guardians...you travel through the land of the Shirishama...
直到看到一座墙 墙很高
until you come to a wall so high it blots out the sun.
再往前走五日
Follow that wall for five days...
可达尽头: 西夏麻族的圣地
finally reaching its end:the head of a giant anaconda.
你听说过?
You know the story.
当然
Of course.
很美的传说
Beautiful legend.
但那是麻库族的传说
I believe, however, it's a legend of the Maku.
也是西夏麻族的
Also the Shirishama.
据我所知不是
Not to my knowledge.
涨潮了 村子就在附近
The water's high now, but the village was here.
进入支流就看得到
Down this fork.
我确定
I know.
我以捕蛇为生
I trap snakes for a living.
我相信你很在行
And I'm sure you're very good at it.
但我对找部落很在行
I locate tribes for a living, and I'm very good at that.
根据我的经验 河水暴涨表示
The water level is high, which by my calculations means...
这附近常淹水
the areas to this side will be flooded...
迫使土族
forcing our tribe, if they wanted to eat...
往高处迁移
to seek higher ground over here.
要往哪走?
Which way?
往这儿走
This way!
卫斯屈 来跟图腾一起拍
Westridge, I want a shot of you with the totem.
盖瑞 你来录音 丹尼 准备好了吗?
Gary, you roll sound. Danny, you ready?
开机了
Camera rolling!
拍摄!
Action!
我们很幸运
Our first piece of luck.
看到了一座西夏麻神像 虽有一些争议
A Shirishama idol, although the subject of some dispute...
我确定!
I know!
不信算了! 下个村就让我下船
Accept it or not. Leave me at the next village.
停!
Cut!
很乐意
With pleasure.
怎么回事?
What the hell was that all about?
我们去录虫鸣声
We're going to go get some wild sound.
当心点
Just be careful.
会的
We will.
待会见
See you guys.
好的
All right.
盖瑞
Gary.
真不可思议
It's unbelievable.
盖瑞
Gary.
什么事?
What?
天啊!
Oh, my God.
等一下
Wait.
你听到了吗?
Do you hear that?
好安静
The silence?
盖瑞 快跑!
Run, Gary!
怎么回事?
What was that?
不知道
I don't know.
马泰 用光照那里
Mateo, shine the light over there.
他们能活着真命大
These two are fortunate to be alive.
怎么回事?
What happened?
你们还好吗?
You guys okay?
不是盖的 好厉害
You should've seen it. What a shot.
他一枪就把它击毙了
This guy blasted this thing coming right at us.
野猪
Wild boar.
利用獠牙
Gores with its tusks.
又狠又准
Goes for the eyes.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
还好
Yeah...
谢了
thanks.
从现在开始 以后晚上都留在船上 没有例外
From now on, everybody stays on board at night. No exceptions.
这是个好主意
That's a smart idea.
马泰 把它宰杀了
Let's cut him up.
够吃一星期
Food for a week.
吃?
Food?
- 该我? - 不 该我
- My turn? - It's my turn.
- 不是 - 是
- No, it isn't. - Yeah, it is.
马泰 你会驾船?
Mateo, do you have control of this vessel!
不会别逞强
Lie if you must!
马泰
Mateo.
绳子缠住推进器了
Goddamn rope's caught in the propeller!
好吧 我去割断绳子
Well, looks like I'll have to cut us loose.
我去会好点 河水有上千种方法可以杀死你
It's maybe better I do it. This river can kill you in a thousand ways.
我没问题
I can handle it.
我只怕线鱼
I'm only really afraid of the candiru acu.
什么?
What?
线鱼 很小的鲶鱼
Candiru acu. It's a tiny little catfish.
它会游入尿道中
It swims up into your urethra...
找个温暖之处 展开尖鳍
finds a nice warm spot, spreads its thorny little spines...
赖着不走
and refuses to budge.
好痛
Ouch.
必须动手术
You have to cut it out.
够了! 我要回洛杉矶
That's it, man. I'm getting the hell back to L.A.
戴芮 不对劲
Terri, something's wrong!
天啊!
My God.
凯尔?
Cale?
他受伤了! 我去
He's hurt. I'm going.
别急 我去!
Hold up. I got him.
盖瑞?
Gary?
快啊!
Hurry up!
游快一点!
Come on, guys!
史堤夫!
Steven!
还有呼吸吗?
Is he breathing?
快一点!
Faster!
他还好吗?
Is he all right?
快点!
Hurry!
当心
Be careful.
怎么回事?
What is it?
氧气罩
Get his mask off.
当心
Careful. Careful.
把他的头垫高
Get something for his head.
他没呼吸了!
He's not breathing!
没呼吸了!
- 把头垫高 - 来了
- Something for his head. - Here.
他嘴里有东西
There's something in the mouth.
天啊
Oh, dear God.
老天 那是什么?
Damn, what's that?
黄蜂
Wasp.
致命的
Deadly.
有毒
Poisonous.
没呼吸了 怎么办?
He's still not breathing. What can we do?
天 怎么会这样?
God, how did this happen?
酒精
Alcohol.
我有威士忌
I got whiskey in my flask.
快!
Quickly.
要干什么?
What's that for?
他呼吸了
He's breathing.
行了
That's it.
他死不了
He'll be all right.
他还好 我们出发!
He seems okay. We should go now.
无线电失灵
That radio don't work.
通讯中断
We have no communication.
我会修 行吗?
Hey, I can't fix, okay?
出发吧!
We can start now.
不有雾
Fog.
赶快送他去医院
If we don't get this man to a hospital soon...
死了只有扔入河里了
we might as well throw him in the river.
什么?
What?
戴芮 我们有照明设备
Terri, we got lights.
好
Good.
马泰
Mateo.
我们尽快回去
We'll just double back.
逆流而上
Fighting the current...
多两天行程
Iose two days.
由支流回去
Cut back to this tributary...
省五十英里
save us 50 miles.
这是你昨天建议的路线
This is the route you suggested we take yesterday.
昨天有不同的理由
Yesterday, for a different reason.
现在是为了送他去医院 可能的话越快越好
Now, our concern is getting Professor Cale to a hospital...as fast as possible.
好吧!
All right.
你要想清楚再决定
I hope you know what you're doing.
我不相信他
I don't know about this dude.
我别无选择
What choice do I have?
这是什么?
What the hell is this?
戴芮 过来
Terri, come here.
这是你说的河道?
This is the river you know?
不
No...
栅栏是新建的
this is new.
但是别惊慌
But no cause for panic.
我没有惊慌 我只是看到...
I'm not panicking. I just see this wall...
你说的河道被堵住了
blocking our way down this river that you know.
好吧 我们想想办法
Well, let's just see what we can do.
那是炸药?
Real dynamite?
以防万一
It's always good to be prepared.
什么万一?
Prepared for what?
别开玩笑 那栅栏在那里一定有它的目的
You must be kidding. That thing must be there for a reason!
不让我们进入
Yeah, to keep us out.
我们有可能会影响河川生态平衡
We can't upset the ecological balance of this river.
听好
Look.
十分钟就可炸掉
I can blow it in ten minutes, or if...
否则就多两天行程
you're feeling sensitive, we can turn around and lose two days.
取决于你们
It's up to you.
戴芮
Terri.
老天! 炸了那东西吧!
For God's sake, blow the bloody thing.
给我十分钟 朋友
Give me ten minutes, people.
只需十分钟
Ten minutes.
我需要帮助
I'll need some help.
盖瑞 把船拉来
Gary? Get that little boat.
有东西在下面
Something's there.
没错
That's right.
不 我说真的
No, I really mean it.
我也是
I really mean it too.
快一点!
Hurry!
妈的! 天! 到处都是蛇!
Shit! Goddamn! Snakes!
- 天啊 - 真恶心!
- Oh, God! - Gross!
小蛇
Babies.
只是小蛇
All babies.
怎么把它们弄走?
How do we get them off the boat?
宝贝们 来
Come on, babies.
回去找妈妈
Back to your mama.
有些不是小蛇
Some aren't babies.
别激动
Calm.
可恶!
Little shit!
萨朗 帮他弄掉!
Sarone, help him get it off!
快来人把这个东西弄走!
Someone get this bloody thing off my frigging hand!
弄走!
Get it off!
这么小就这么凶
So young and yet so lethal.
快弄走!
Get it off me.
快点
Come on.
宝贝 再见
Later, sweetie.
你知道有蛇 对不对 萨朗?
You knew there were snakes here, didn't you, Sarone?
这是个意外的惊喜
Was a pleasant surprise.
燃油怎么办?
What about the fuel?
只剩一桶 只够走一百公里
There's only one drum left. Enough for 100 kilometers.
约一天行程
About a day's ride.
该足够了
That will have to do.
去去找妈妈
Go back to your mother.
他还好吗?
How's he doing?
呼吸正常了
He's breathing normally now.
很好
That's good.
我们会平安回去的
We'll get him home.
我不懂是怎么回事
I just don't know what's going on.
萨朗应该带我们去医院
Sarone's supposed to get us back to the hospital, right?
他好像很了解这河道
And he acts like he owns this river...
但是他却带我们闯进栅栏里
and we run into a barrier...
都是蛇
full of snakes.
他想带我们去哪里?
I mean, where is he taking us?
马泰
Mateo.
停船!
Stop the boat!
停!
Stop it!
为什么停船?
Why are we stopping now?
那里会有燃油
There'll be fuel.
你见过那艘船?
You know that boat?
很多船都长那样子
There's lots of boats like that.
哈啰!
Hello!
我肯定没人在船上
I get the distinct impression there's nobody home.
马泰 跟我来
Mateo. Come with me.
等一下
Hold up.
我去拍下来
I'll get this on film.
你不需要配音吧!
You don't need sound, do you?
我才不去
I'm not going.
你去船尾
Go aft.
萨朗?
Sarone?
这里阴森森的
Kind of spooky in here.
是吗?
Think so?
这是什么?
What the...
- 帮我搬这个 - 那是什么?
- Help me with this. - What's that?
宝藏
Treasures.
拿着
There.
当心! 我的摄影机
Be careful. I put my camera in here.
马泰 好 走了!
Mateo, that's it! Let's go!
我来了!
Hey, I'm coming!
来了!
I'm coming!
这是什么?
What's all this?
- 燃油呢? - 没有燃油
- What about the fuel? - There was no fuel.
马泰呢?
Where's Mateo?
不知道
I don't know.
就在后面
He was right behind us.
马泰?
Mateo?
我回去找
I'm going back.
萨朗 陪他去
Sarone, go with him.
也许改天吧!
Maybe some other time.
浑球!
Asshole.
我们停留在这个鬼地方而驾驶却不见了
Stuck in the middle of nowhere and we've lost the driver.
马泰
Mateo.
伙计 出来 别闹了!
Come on, man. Stop playing!
丹尼?
Danny?
在这里
Yeah!
你还好吗?
You okay?
我没事!
I'm all right!
没找到他
Didn't see him!
多令人放心!
How reassuring.
你还好吗?
You okay?
没事
Yeah.
- 只找到这个 - 只有这个?
- This is it. - This is all you found?
是的
Yeah.
这是什么?
What the hell is this?
巨蟒脱的皮
Anaconda skin.
蛇有这么大?
There's snakes out there this big?
这是三 四岁的蛇
This skin is three or four years old.
现在一定更大了
Whatever shed it has grown since then.
这只巨蟒吃了我们的驾驶
Something like this has made a meal of our dear captain.
什么?
What?
蛇不吃人
Snakes don't eat people.
是吗?
They don't?
巨蟒是完美的杀人机器
Anacondas are a perfect killing machine.
它们有热感应器
They have heat sensors.
马泰的体温在水中很容易侦测
A warm body like Mateo's in the water wasn't hard to find.
它们攻击你 缠住你
They strike, wrap around you...
比爱人抱得还紧
hold you tighter than your true love...
在死前将你听到自己骨头碎裂声
and you get the privilege of hearing your bones break...
血管被压挤得根根爆裂
before the power of the embrace causes your veins to explode.
马泰可能迷路了
No, Mateo's probably just lost.
别做梦了!
Wake up!
若能活捉到这只巨蟒
Imagine something this big captured alive.
将非常值钱 盖瑞
Worth a lot of money, Gary.
真是的!
Jesus.
各位 拜托
Please, people...
别把我当怪物看
don't make me out a monster.
不是我吃了马泰的
I didn't eat the captain Mateo.
各位 打起精神
Come on, everybody.
我们不确定马泰已死
We are not sure Mateo is dead.
我们等到明天早上
We're going to wait here till morning.
你疯了?
Are you insane?
你认为他会去哪里? 难道他去丛林散步了?
Where do you think he went? A walk in the woods!
听着 我们必须赶快离开这里!
Listen. We've got to get the hell out of here.
你冷静点!
Get a grip!
我很冷静!
I've got a grip!
我们不走 换做你 也会希望我们等
If it was you out there, you'd want us to stay!
换做是我早就死了 你不明白吗?
If it was me out there, I'd be dead! Don't you see?
回房里 锁上门
Go into your cabin and lock the door.
像被禁足
Like a bad boy.
好吧
All right, all right.
我的鞋呢?
Where are my shoes?
将灯打在那船上
We're gonna aim some lights at the boat.
好主意
That's a good idea.
灯光是好主意
Lights are a good idea.
说不定是他吃了马泰
I'm not so sure he didn't eat the captain.
他看起来很满足的样子
He sure looks satiated.
你猜他还活着吗?
Think he's still alive?
算了 去睡吧!
No. Let's go to bed.
危险
Danger.
又很刺激 对吗 盖瑞?
Danger is exciting. Huh, Gary?
你先去睡 我就来
Go on to bed. I'll catch up to you.
盖瑞
Garry.
我跟他说句话就来
I'm just going to talk for a second and then catch up to you.
快点 我好怕
Hurry up. I'm scared.
我就来
I'll be right there.
那么...巨蟒在附近?
So, it's out there, isn't it?
是的
Yep.
你知道如何捕捉?
And you know how to catch these things?
没错
That's right.
但一个人无法捉巨蟒 需要伙伴帮忙
But you can't catch an anaconda by yourself. You need a partner.
活捉
Capture alive...
或许值上百万 盖瑞
maybe a million dollars, Gary.
(爬虫类镇静剂)
没马泰的影子
Still no Mateo.
卫斯屈 保持平稳
Keep it steady, Westridge!
稳着点!
Steady it!
你干什么?
What the fuck are you doing?
抓巨蟒不能没有饵
Can't catch anacondas without bait.
天啊!
My God.
卫斯屈 走吧!
Westridge, let's go.
不! 等等!
No, stop!
不能用我的船
Not on my boat.
你的船? 你代表大家?
Your boat? You speak for everybody?
盖瑞?
Garry?
她代表大家吗?
She speak for everybody?
盖瑞?
Garry?
因为凯尔受伤 电影也拍不成了
The way I figure it, with Cale messed up the movie's off.
我们得另谋他途
Why not salvage something?
我们拍萨朗抓蛇的镜头
Let's film Sarone capturing a big snake.
你疯了?
Have you lost your mind?
我疯了? 不 我清醒得很
No, I haven't! If anything, I'm completely lucid now.
你们才应该睁大眼睛想清楚
I think it's you guys who need to open your eyes.
等一下
Hold up.
我们要送凯尔去医院 怎么能抓蛇?
How we go from taking Cale to the hospital to catching a goddamn snake?
知道你们身在何处? 你们在丛林中当中!
Do you know where you are? You're in the middle of the jungle!
你们不断怀疑 抱怨
All you guys do is question and criticize.
但是请记住 你们对这地方屁都不懂
But remember, you don't know shit about the shit we're in out here...
我也不懂
and neither do I, okay?
但我知道谁懂 就是他
But I guarantee you I know who does. This guy.
保罗来过这里 如果帮他捕蛇
Paul has been here, and if we help him catch the snake...
他会带我们平安回去
he'll help us get out of here alive.
所以这不是发疯 那是极为合理的判断
That, amigos, is not insanity. That is common freaking sense!
盖瑞 别这样
Come on, Gary...
这不是你
this isn't you.
- 他把你怎么了? - 够了! 别说了!
- What did he do to you? - Stop, okay?
想想看这样值多少钱
Think about how much money this would be worth.
将前所未见的巨蟒
Imagine capturing something like this on film...
拍入镜?
for the first time ever.
何况 我们别无选择
Honestly, what else are we supposed to do?
还有选择
I know what I'm gonna do.
把你们丢进河里
I'll throw both y'all son of a bitches in the river myself.
不好吧
I don't think so.
我不希望发生这种事 朋友
I didn't want this to happen, people!
- 出发吧! 卫斯屈! - 好吧
- Let's go, Westridge! - Okay.
盖瑞
Garry.
你们找点事做
Occupy yourselves.
玩玩牌
Play some cards.
都别动
Nobody move.
盖瑞 开灯!
Garry! Get the lights!
卫斯屈 停船!
Westridge, stop the boat!
停!
Stop it!
晚安 美人
Buenas noches, beautiful.
卫斯屈 下来
Get down here, Westridge!
你会害我们送命!
You'll get us all killed!
对! 照着它!
That's it!
照眼睛!
Go for the eyes!
让它看不见!
Blind it!
天啊 你在钓蛇!
Christ. You're fishing for a snake!
他疯了
That man gotta be crazy.
放了它
Just let it go!
卫斯屈 下来!
Westridge, come down here!
巨蟒呢?
Where is it?
别动! 我用麻醉枪
Don't move! I'll get it with a tranquilizer!
荻妮 上来 快!
Denise, get up here!
盖瑞 救我!
Gary, help!
救我!
Help me!
快上来!
Get out of there!
抓住她!
Grab her!
我卡住了!
I'm stuck!
抓住她!
Grab her!
巨蟒! 在水里
The snake! It's in the water!
快!
Let's go!
盖瑞!
Garry!
盖瑞 抓住我手
Gary, give me your hand!
盖瑞!
Garry!
不! 我要活捉它
It's no good to me dead!
不! 天!
Oh, no! God!
愿死者的灵魂蒙主恩
May the souls of the faithful depart through mercy of God...
获得安息 阿门
rest in peace. Amen.
卫斯屈
Westridge!
你真大胆!
How dare you!
是你把蛇引来的
It was you who brought that snake.
你带来魔鬼
You brought the devil.
每人内心都有魔鬼
There's a devil inside everyone.
- 你别碰她 - 真可怕
- Get your hands off her. - Horrible.
卫斯屈!
Westridge!
把我的装备拿到驾驶室
Take my gear up to the pilothouse.
我不是你的佣人
I'm not your bloody poodle.
你说什么?
What did you say?
你命令我吗?
How dare you presume to order me about?
是这样吗?
That so?
我把你扔进河里 怎么样?
How you like I "presume" to throw you in the river?
拿到上面去
Take it upstairs.
谢谢
Thank you.
其余的人别动
Everyone else... don't move.
退后
Get back.
戴芮 我们要谈谈
Terri, let's talk.
你要什么?
You want something?
只想跟你谈
I just want to talk to you.
我在想那神话
I was thinking about the myth.
我不知道你是否知道
I don't know if you know...
这影片是我的机会
but this film was supposed to be my big break.
却变成了大灾难
But it's turned out to be a big disaster.
我在想也许
I was just thinking...
我可以拍摄你
maybe I could film you...
捕捉蛇 然后...
capturing the snake, and then...
这次行程就不算白费
it wouldn't all be for nothing.
我不晓得 也许有危险
I don't know. It could be dangerous.
我知道
I know...
但至少有你会保护我们
but at least you'd be there to protect us.
你需要保护?
You need protection?
是的
Yeah.
我已有很久
It's been a long time...
没和女人做爱
since I had a woman.
你以为我那么傻?
Think I'm stupid!
我不傻!
I'm not stupid!
成功了!
It worked!
一击即中 要再打他吗?
Asshole in one. Shall I hit him again?
我们把他扔下河!
Throw him in the river!
好了 足够了
Haven't we had enough?
我倒想丢他下去
I'm ashamed to say I rather enjoyed it.
把他捆起来
Let's just tie him up.
这是个设计好的圈套 对吗
This was all one big setup?
马泰
Mateo.
你被困
You stranded.
那失事的船
The shipwrecked boat.
你往医院的途径
Your route to the hospital.
你怎么能忘记那只黄蜂
How could you forget about the wasp?
你所做的并不难
What you do is not so hard.
我也会捉蛇
I can trap a snake too.
你虽聪明
As smart as you are...
但没有我你活不成
you can't survive without me.
我们很快就到家了
We're going to be home soon.
真不敢相信你康复得这么快
I can't believe how good you're doing.
支持下去 宝贝
Hang in there, baby.
驶船很难吗?
Is it hard to drive?
就像开一辆凯迪拉克一样
It's like driving a Cadillac Fleetwood.
告诉你 我要来教你怎么开动这个大家伙
Tell you what. I'll give you a driving lesson.
黑色拉杆
Black knobs:
向上推向前走 向下是倒退
Up to go forward, down to go back.
红色拉杆
Red knobs:
向上快行 向下慢行
Up to go fast, down to go slow.
驾驶盘 四次用力扭向左或右
Wheel: Four turns hard over, left and right.
遇上麻烦 关掉发火装置
If you get into trouble, turn off the ignition.
你试试看
Take it for a spin.
就这样?
That's it?
送我们回文明吧
Take us back to civilization.
没问题
Shit, no problem.
送我们回去享受
Take us back to...
洁净的床单及热水浴
crisp sheets and hot showers.
看球赛决赛及喝啤酒
The play-offs and a six-pack.
打十八洞高球
Eighteen holes of golf and...
喝琴酒
a quadruple gin and tonic.
洛市的塞车和我的行动电话
L.A. Traffic and my cellular phone.
别说了
Don't start.
瀑布
The waterfall.
真壮观 小丫头
It's a beautiful sight, baby bird.
传说没有错
The legend was right.
这是什么地方?
What is this place?
天啊
Oh, dear.
真是美极了
It's absolutely beautiful.
怎么回事?
What the hell was that?
我想我们撞上河底了
I think we hit the bottom.
没错!
We did.
用力向左转
Turn the wheel hard to the left.
好 用后档
Right. Put it in reverse.
关引擎!
Shut it down!
妈的
Shit.
我们得想办法
We got to winch ourself loose.
且慢! 你想干嘛?
Wait. What are you doing?
要进到水中?
That means getting in the water.
没别的办法
We ain't got much choice.
我们将绳索缠好绑在那棵树上
Lfigure me and you can go...and wrap a rope around that tree.
你去把绳索绑在那棵树上
You, wrap a rope around that tree.
一定要绑紧 否则我们就永远回不去了
Pull it tight. If not, we stuck here forever.
动作快 绑完就回来
We got to make it quick. In and out.
我做的事够多了
I rather hoped I'd done my bit.
我们的绳子
That's our rope.
只够绕到树那里
Just enough to go around the tree. Right?
拿去这个 把它绑在树干上 确定要绑紧
Take this. Get it around the trunk right there. Make sure it's secure.
好
Right you are.
我讨厌这样 上次我像这样下到水里
I hate this. Last time I was in water like this...
水蛭爬到我阴囊上了
I was up all night picking leeches off my scrotum.
要死前祈祷?
Aren't you going to pray?
永远别注视你要杀的猎物
Never look in the eyes of those you kill.
那将成为永远的梦魇 我知道
They will haunt you forever. I know.
我立志宣誓
Lfirmly resolve...
求神恩典
with help and grace...
洗清我罪行
to confess my sins, do penance...
给我自新机会 阿门
and to amend my life! Amen.
众神保佑...
Sanctus...
...这小丫头
...baby bird.
快
Hurry up.
回船上! 快!
Back on the boat! Now!
快点!
Come on!
快啊
Go!
天啊
Christ!
回船上! 快!
On the boat! Go on! Hurry!
快!
Quick!
Go!
快啊 它就在你身后
Hurry, it's there!
上船!
Go!
大肥蛇! 看这里
Over here, you fat-ass bastard.
惨了!
Shit!
- 爬上岩石! - 快去!
- The rocks! - Go!
爬上去!
Get up the rocks!
它来了!
It's coming!
该死! 去拿枪!
Damn! Get the gun!
我们怎么办?
What are we gonna do?
拿枪来!
Get it!
快去!
Hurry up!
继续爬!
Keep going, man!
丹尼 当心!
Danny! Watch out!
丹尼 让开
Danny! Move your arm!
当心!
Look out!
丹尼
Danny!
卫斯屈
Westridge!
糟了!
Shit!
快上来!
Hurry up!
卡住了
I'm caught.
来吧! 快来!
Come on. Hurry up.
来吧!
Come on!
丹尼! 不! 给我你的手!
Danny, no! Give me your arm!
丹尼 撑着!
Danny! Hold on!
我拿到枪了
I got it.
撑着!
Hold on!
上来
Come on.
你杀了我的巨蟒!
You killed my warrior snake!
起来
Get up.
麻醉枪
The dart.
麻醉剂生效了 上!
The tranquilizer's working. Get him.
可恶! 麻醉剂掉了
Damn, the dart came out his back.
走 回床上去
Come on. Almost there.
好了
All right.
宝贝
Baby?
他又昏迷了
He lost consciousness again.
我试着去开船 船脱离河床了
I'll try to get us out of here. The tree knocked us loose.
戴芮 你看!
Terri, look.
那里可能有燃油
It might have some fuel for us.
我们去看看
Let's check it out.
要我扶吗?
Need some help?
不用了 我没事
No. I'm cool.
我不想知道曾发生什么事
I don't even want to know what happened here.
我也是
Me neither.
希望他们这里有燃油
Hope they got some fuel though.
那些桶子可能是燃油
Those drums could be fuel.
蛇蜕的皮
A snake skin.
这儿有很多燃油
There's plenty of fuel here.
欢迎!
Welcome!
该起床了
Time to wake up.
猴血
Monkey blood.
我要宰了你! 萨朗! 我发誓!
I'll kill you, Sarone! I swear to God!
别惹我发火
Don't get me upset.
看这个?
See this?
人骨
Human bones.
生命的尽头
That's how it comes out.
尘归尘
Ashes to ashes.
糟了!
Oh, shit!
糟了! 你看!
Shit, look!
站起来
Up, on your feet.
快!
Come on.
走!
Go!
抓到了!
Gotcha!
松开
Get loose.
拿了燃油就走
Let's get the fuel and get out.
别管了 走!
Don't worry. Just go!
快跑 它追来了!
Run! It's coming for you!
丹尼 你在哪里?
Danny, where are you?
是蛇窝
There's a nest.
我让它追我上烟囱
I'll have him chase me up the smokestack!
不! 我脚没受伤
No! I've got the legs.
好 我们可以把它引进去
Ok, We can trap it there.
跑!
Go!
你能爬出去吗?
Can you climb out the top?
我可以用这条绳子!
I can use the rope!
快! 我要炸飞了它!
Hurry! I can blow him up!
我点火了!
I'm gonna light it!
干吧! 我上来了!
Go ahead! I'm at the top!
该死
Damn.
丹尼
Danny!
点燃了!
The fuse is lit!
等一下!
Wait!
推边缘 用力!
Hit the hinges!
快! 跳下来!
Hurry! You got to jump!
不 太高了!
I can't! It's too high!
快跳!
Just jump!
好了 来
I got you. Come on.
我们杀了它? 是吗?
Did we get him? Did we!
是的
We got him.
你还好吗?
You all right?
还好
Yeah.
我们这就去拿燃油 然后就离开这里
We should get the fuel, so we can get the hell out of here.
好吗?
All right?
来吧
Come on.
贱货
Bitch.
我们走
Let's go.
芙勒薇小姐
Miss Flores...
你真狼狈
you're a mess.
找到绷带了
Found another one.
我看伤口
Let me see that.
西夏麻族
Shirishama.
萨朗说得对
Sarone was right.
丹尼
Danny.
该死
Damn.
我去拿摄影机
I'll get the camera.
好主意
I think so.
- 拍摄 - 开机了
- Roll film. - Camera rolling.